

ROYCHELLE ROWDEN

VISUAL + USER INTERFACE DESIGNER

SUMMARY

What is life about if you can't reinvent yourself? After several years of working as a landscape architect I felt my career prospects beginning to stagnate. My ability to find new employment began to narrow as firms increasingly closed their doors I had to make a choice to persevere on my current path or pivot and learn new in demand skills.

In 2013 I finally took a leap of faith and joined Startup Institute's program for Product Design, which helped me develop the skills to gain a position as a User Interface Designer. My goal is to be a part of a design-focused team in Austin TX creating cutting edge work that solve problems and provide the best possible experience.

WORK HISTORY

2014 - present

User Interface Designer

Skidmore Owings & Merrill LLP - Chicago, IL

As the sole designer on my team I am responsible for driving all stages of the creation of interfaces that help SOM staff manage, digest and disseminate information. My duties include:

- Building low and high fidelity prototypes that communicate interactions to development team.
- Implementing UI with development team and created enhancements to optimize user experience.
- Customizing Drupal, Wordpress sites and other platforms so they are cohesive with SOM branding standards.

2013 - 2014

Freelance Designer

SoPact, In2itive Marketing & Classroom IQ - Chicago, IL Created branding, interface and Drupal site customization for small startups.

2007 - 2013

Associate

Hoerr Schaudt Landscape Architects - Chicago, IL
Project management of sites varying in scale and location. Production of
construction documents, details and specifications 3D Modeling and photorealistic image

construction documents, details and specifications 3D Modeling rendering concept design to construction.

EDUCATION

2013 - 2013

Product & Design

StartUp Institute - Chicago, IL

2003 - 2006 Master of Landscape Architecture

Louisiana State University College - Baton Rouge, LA

1999 - 2003 Bachelor of Arts in Biology & Studio Art Knox College - Galesburg, IL

TOOLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JQuery
- Bootstrap
- Visual Studio

- InVision
- Drupal
- Wordpress
- Photoshop
- Illustrator

- Indesign
- Powerpoint
- Word
- Excel

SKILLS

- Responsive Design
- Prototyping

- Wireframing
- Personas

- Branding Design
- User Testing